Has your so-called test
produced a result?
(ネジ)あなたの言う
実験の結果は出ましたか？
彼らは里の掟より
仲間どうしの絆を➡
I believe it's already been proven that
they consider the bonds of friendship
大事にすることを
証明してくれたはずです。
more important than
the rules of the village.
もう 実験をする必要は
ないでしょう。
Hmm… So there's no need to
continue this test.
今まで さらった
木ノ葉の忍たち 全員を➡
You will release all the Hidden Leaf
Shinobi you've abducted, right…?
返してくださいますね？
父上。
Father?
(綱手)なに 仮面の男はネジの？
What?
The Masked Man is Neji's—?!
(シズネ)そろそろ
これが必要かと思いまして。
I figured it was about time
you'd want this…
お～ 気が利くな。
How thoughtful of you!
どうぞ。
Here you go.
おっとっとっと…。
Whoa…
あ～ 五臓六腑に染み渡るな！
That sure hits the spot!
おっと 続き 続き。
All right, the continuation…
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
The Caged Bird
いいだろう。
That's fine…
消えたみんなは
どこにいるんです？
Where are you keeping everyone?
無事なんでしょうね？
I trust they're safe…
Of course.
むろんだ
すぐ道案内をさせよう。
I'll have the three lead you
to them immediately.
You can go and gather everyone.
お前は 皆を迎えに行ってくれ。
わかりました。
All right.
俺は 後始末をしてから合流する。
I have to tie up some loose ends,
I'll join you afterwards.
(シカマル)みんな聞いたな？
You got that, everyone?
We're joining up as one team
俺たちは 一致団結し
アスマたちを➡
to look for Asuma, I mean our friends,
and rescue them!
仲間たちを見つけて
助け出す！
(ナルトたち)おぉ！
Right!
All right, let's get going!
(ナルト)よし すぐに行くってばよ。
Hold it, Naruto.
ちょっと待て ナルト！
なんだよ。
What is it?
You're the one who said
we're going to rescue our friends!
仲間を助け出すって
お前が言ったんだろ？
言ったけどよ。
Yeah, I did.
But we don't even know
where they are.
みんながどこにいるか
まったく わかってないんだぜ。
(いの)手がかりもないし…。
Not even one clue…
(リー)それとも ナルト君は
僕たちが知らない情報を➡
Unless, Naruto,
you have intel that we don't.
持っているんですか？
(テンテン)そうそう。
Yeah, yeah!
そ… そんなもん
あるわけねえだろうが。
You think I'd have
that kind of intel?
(みんな)あ～？
– Huh?
(サスケ)フンッ 戦闘力は多少上がったが
頭のできは悪いままだな。
Your fighting skills
may've improved slightly,
but your brain's still the same.
何だと!?
(サクラ)もう ケンカはやめて！
What?!
Hey! Stop fighting!
(キバ)やっぱ 俺たち探索班の
出番だな。
I guess that's
the Tracking Team's cue…
(赤丸)ワン！
I don't think you'll be needed…
(ヒナタ)その必要はなさそうだよ。
あ？
Huh?!
ワン！ ワン！
ネジ兄さん… よくご無事で。
Neji, I'm glad you're safe.
心配をかけたな。
Sorry to have worried you.
おい 敵はどうなった？
やっつけちまったのか!?
What happened to the enemy?
– Did you bring him down?
– No.
いや。
えっ 逃がしちまったのか？
You let him get away?
(ネジ)いや そうじゃないが…。
No, that's not it, but…
Then what happened?
だったら
どういうことだってばよ!?
Naruto!
Give Neji a chance to speak.
ナルト ネジに話す時間を与えようぜ。
ったく…。
Damn it.
あ… あぁ。
Oh, okay…
で どうなんだ？ ネジ。
So? What's going on, Neji?
(飛段)やっと お出ましか。
Finally, we're up.
あ～あ 待ちくたびれたぜ。
I've been bored to death.
実験は終わった。
The test is over.
これをもって
傭兵諸君には解散していただく。
So I'm dismissing the mercenaries.
(ヒルコ)そうはいかねえな。
見てくれ。
You can't do that.
Take a look.
(ヒルコ)俺の芸術に
傷をつけられたまま➡
My art has been damaged and
you expect me to just leave?
引き下がれというのか？
もう すべては終わった。
Everything is complete.
真実を証明することもできた。
解散だ。
I was able to verify the truth.
You're dismissed.
おっ 待てよ 相棒！
Huh? Hey wait, partner!
The job's complete.
(角都)仕事は終わった。
カネをもらえば もう用はない。
Once we get paid, we're done.
チッ！ しようがねえな。
Guess it can't be helped.
あっ？ えっ!?
ちょっ… 待ってくれよ！
Huh?! Huh?!
H-Hey! Wait a second!
お前たちには後始末を頼みたい。
I'd like you to tie up
some loose ends.
(小南)後始末… ですか？
"Loose ends" you say?
避難していた住民たちを
もとの家に戻してくれ。
Help the evacuated villagers
return to their homes.
(弥彦)あぁ 喜んで。
We'll be happy to do that.
And there's one more thing
I'd like to request…
それとは別に
やってほしいことがある。
というわけだ。
Anyway, that's it.
つまり 今まで起こったことは➡
So you're saying everything
that happened
was just an experiment
by this masked man?
すべて その仮面の男の
実験だったっつうことか。
ちょっと待ってください！
ガイ先生たちは無事なんですか？
Hold on!
Guy Sensei and the others
are safe?
あぁ 人質全員の解放を約束して
道案内を用意すると言っていた。
Yeah. He promised he'd free
all the hostages and lead us to them.
道案内って？
何だ？ それ。
"Lead us to them"?
What does that mean?
なんだ お前ら！
Who the hell are you guys?!
(小南)私たちは敵ではないわ。
We're not your enemy.
(弥彦)まずは信頼関係を
築かなきゃな。
First of all, we want to show you
a sign of mutual trust.
今回は 雇い主の試験に
巻き込んですまなかった。
We apologize for getting you
involved in our employer's test.
(長門)試験は終了した。
キミたちの仲間は解放する。
The test is over.
Your friends will be freed.
本当か？
Are you serious?
We are Hidden Rain Shinobi.
俺たちは 雨隠れの忍。
忍の世界の未来のため➡
We travel around the land
in search of those
同じ志を持った仲間を探し
旅を続けている チーム・ジライヤだ。
who share our vision for
the future of the shinobi world.
We're Team Jiraiya.
ウソは…。
チーム・ジライヤ!?
Team Jiraiya?!
おめえら エロ仙人を知ってんのか？
You guys know Pervy Sage?
ああ 僕たちの命の恩人であり
忍術の師匠だ。
Yes. He saved our lives and
he was our ninjutsu master.
I get it now.
(シカマル)なるほど 襲撃されながらも
殺意を感じなかったのは➡
When we were attacked,
I didn't sense any malice.
試験だったからか。
Because it was just a test.
で 俺たちは
その試験にパスしたってことか？
So, did we pass the test?
だと思う。 なのでこれから
仲間の居場所を教える。
I believe so.
That's why we're telling you
where your friends are.
小南。
Konan.
シノビアゲハ。
Shinobi Ageha Butterflies…
The butterflies will guide you
to your friends.
蝶たちが あなたたちを
仲間のところへ案内するわ。
俺たちは 村人たちを もとの家に
戻さなきゃなんねえんだ。
We must go return
the villagers to their homes.
そろそろ消えさせてもらうぜ。
So we'll be leaving.
ちょっと待て！
Hold it.
ちえっ エロ仙人とのこと
もっと聞きたかったのに。
Damn it! I wanted to hear more
about Pervy Sage.
あれについて行けばいいんだな。
So we just follow…them?
ネジ兄さん。
ああ。
Neji…
(ヒナタ)シノビアゲハ。
Shinobi Ageha Butterflies…
あそこ！
あの建物か。
They're over there!
That structure, huh?
All right!
Let's go save everyone!
よ～し
みんなを助けに行くってばよ！
待てよ 万が一
罠ってことだって…。
Wait! There could be traps—
He's not even listening.
聞いてないし。
ったく。
Damn it.
みんな！
Everyone!
(カカシ)面目ない。
This is embarrassing.
ガイ先生 ご無事でなによりです。
Guy Sensei,
I'm so glad you're okay.
Oh! I'm super-overcome
with emotion!
(ガイ)おお！ 俺は今
むちゃくちゃ感動しているぞ！
教え子に助けられるとは
先生冥利に尽きるというもの。
To be rescued by my pupil
is more than I ever deserve…
くは～っ！
Ouch!
あちっ…
もう少し 丁寧にやってくれ。
Can you be a little gentler?
たいした傷じゃないって。
But it's just a scratch.
アスマ。
(チョウジ)どこか
痛いとこあったりしない？
Asuma…
Are you hurt anywhere?
No…
(アスマ)いや…
心配をかけて すまなかった。
Sorry we made you worry.
ほんと よかった～。
I'm so relieved.
しかし 今回の事件➡
Anyway, what was this incident
all about anyway?
いったい どういうことなんだ？
Are you guys able
to explain it to us?
(紅)あなたたち
説明してくれるわね。
Y-Yeah.
あ… ああ。
Allow me to me explain.
私から説明しよう。
Wait.
待ってくれ。
もう この人は敵ではない！
He's no longer our enemy!
It's all right.
大丈夫だ。
わかったってばよ。
Okay, then.
まさか… あなたは。
No way…You're—!
You're…Hizashi Hyuga…
あなたは… 日向ヒザシさん。
(ヒナタ)そんな…。
Impossible…
あなたは 私が３歳の時
亡くなられたはずじゃ…。
You're supposed to have died
when I was three years old…
え？
そこは まず俺から説明しよう。
What?
Well, let me explain that part.
ネジ兄さん…。
Neji…
ヒナタ様 ３歳の誕生日に➡
When Lady Hinata
was three years old,
a major crisis hit
the Hidden Leaf Village.
木ノ葉を揺るがす
大事件が起きた。
雲隠れの忍に
ヒナタ様が さらわれかけ➡
Shinobi from the Hidden Cloud
attempted to kidnap you…
ヒアシ様が
返り討ちにしてしまわれたのだ。
but Lord Hiashi killed them.
(ヒナタ)悪いのは
もちろん 雲隠れのほう。
The Hidden Cloud was at fault.
当然 里の関係は悪化し
戦いになりかけた。
Naturally, relations became strained
and the threat of war loomed.
戦いを避けたい木ノ葉は➡
In order to prevent fighting,
雲隠れと裏取引をし
雲の条件をのんだ。
the Hidden Leaf secretly negotiated
with the Hidden Cloud
and accepted their conditions.
いや のまざるをえなかった。
Rather, they had no choice
but to accept.
なんだってばよ その条件って…。
What was the condition?
白眼の血継限界を持つ
日向宗家…。
The head of the Hyuga who possessed
the Kekkei Genkai, the Byakugan.
つまり ヒナタ様の父上➡
In other words, they demanded
the Leaf hand over
the corpse of Lady Hinata's father,
Hiashi Hyuga.
ヒアシ様の死体を
渡せというものだった。
そこで 日向ヒアシと
双子の兄弟である➡
And so,
Hiashi Hyuga's younger twin,
俺の父 日向ヒザシが
宗家の影武者として➡
my father Hizashi Hyuga
became his stand-in…
殺されることで
里の平和が守られたんだ。
and peace in the village
was maintained.
父上の決意と いきさつは
ナルト お前が見たとおりだ。
As for my father's decision and
the circumstances behind that,
you saw it for yourself, Naruto.
それも これも
宗家を守るため➡
The terrible system
of the Curse Mark
that's been passed down within the Hyuga
to protect the Main Family.
日向に代々伝わる
忌まわしき呪印システム。
生きながらにして
逆らうことのできない➡
We are alive, but are unable to
change the currents of fate.
運命に流されながらも➡
What you saw was my father,
who by his own will,
自らの意志で
運命に逆らおうとした➡
chose to defy his fate.
父上の生き様だったんだ。
(ヒザシ)カカシ こたびのこと
皆に 迷惑をかけた。
Kakashi…
This has caused everyone
much stress.
死んだはずのあなたが なぜ？
You're supposed to be dead,
so how—?
うむ… 最初
私にもわからなかった。
At first,
I didn't understand either.
長い眠りから覚めたとき➡
But after a long slumber,
I awakened…
私は とある男のアジトにいた。
…and found myself within
a certain man's hideout.
((大蛇丸 : あなたが
よみがえったのは➡
You have been revived
thanks to my Reanimation Jutsu.
私の術 穢土転生のおかげ。
でも あなたの心に➡
But it was also because your heart
still had attachments to this world.
この世に対する執着が
あったからでもあるのよ。
執着などない！
私は望んでこの命を…。
I have no attachments.
I wanted to die…
…for the sake of the clan.
一族のために 望んで
その命を捧げたというのね。
It was your wish to
give up your life, you say?
(でも その死が
無駄だったとしたら…))
But if your death was in vain…
その男が言うとおりかもしれない。
Perhaps that man was right.
その時 私はそう思った。
I did feel that way at the time.
そこで 今回の事件を
計画したんだ。
That is why I planned
this incident.
私の死が
無駄ではなかったことを…。
I hoped that my death
was not in vain…
私の死を受け
悪しき掟や運命が➡
That my death would
provide the impetus…
for the Hidden Leaf Village
to rethink
木ノ葉の里に考えるきっかけを➡
the cruel rules and destinies
which took away my life…
もたらしているで
あろうことを期待して…。
いや そんなことは
今はどうでもいい。
Well, all that doesn't
matter anymore.
私は この世に
存在してはならぬ人間だ。
I'm a man who should
not exist in this world.
However, it seems I cannot
undo this jutsu myself.
しかし この術は
自ら解くことは不可能なようだ。
里に戻り この術の解き方を
調べてもらいたい。
I want you to return to the village and
look into how to release this jutsu.
その前に ひとつ。 ネジと…。
But before that…
I would like to speak
with my son Neji, alone.
息子と２人だけで
話をさせてもらいたい。
ネジ あの日のことを
覚えているか？
Neji, do you remember that day?
((ヒザシ : ネジ お前は生きろ。
Neji… You must survive.
お前は 一族の誰よりも➡
You have been blessed with
the gifts of the Hyuga,
日向の才に愛された男だ。
more so than anyone else
in the clan.
(お前を 宗家に
生んでやりたかったなぁ))
How I wish you had been
born into the main family.
Although it was to protect
the village, our clan, and you,
里や家族 そして
お前を守るためとはいえ➡
日向の運命に逆らってみた結果➡
the result of defying
the fate of the Hyuga,
お前には 寂しい思いを
させてしまったな。
has brought you nothing
but sadness.
そのうえで 一族の運命に縛られた
お前の未来が気がかりだった。
On top of that,
I was worried about your future,
tied as it was to
the Hyuga's destiny.
ああ 当然 あなたを失った俺は➡
Yes.
It was only natural,
having lost you,
日向の運命を憎しみ
呪うことをバネにして生きてきた。
I used that as motivation
to live every day
resenting and cursing
my destiny as a Hyuga.
しかし 一人の下忍との出会いが
俺の考え方を変えてくれた。
But meeting a certain genin
changed my way of thinking.
((ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…。
I'm destined to bear the burden
of a mark I can never remove…
(ネジ)一生ぬぐい落とせぬ
印を背負う運命がどんなものか➡
お前などにわかるものか！
How can you possibly
even understand?!
わかってるってばよ。
I do understand.
んで それが何？
And, so what of it?
フン！ かっこつけんじゃねえよ！
Quit trying to show off.
別に てめえだけが
特別じゃねえんだってばよ！
You're not the only one
who's special.
みんな 自分の運命に逆らおうって
必死なんだ！
Everyone is desperate to
defy their own destiny.
お前だって そうだろう。
You're no different.
ぜってえ お前倒して
それを証明してやる！
I'm definitely gonna bring you down
and prove it to you!
日向の憎しみの
運命だかなんだか知らねえがな➡
The Hyuga destiny of whatever
that you despise…
お前が 無理だっつうんなら
もう何もしなくていい！
If it's too much for you,
then forget about it and
don't do anything.
俺が 火影になってから…。
When I become the Hokage…
(日向を変えてやるよ!!))
I'll change…the Hyuga!
(ネジ)うずまきナルト
やつに教えられた。
Naruto Uzumaki taught me.
籠の鳥だって賢くなれば
自分のクチバシでフタを開けようとする。
That even a caged bird,
if it's smart enough,
will use its beak
to open the latch…
また 自由に
空を飛びたいと思うってことを。
Because it wants to fly
free across the sky.
In any case, maybe I'll end up
in the same place.
どちらにせよ 行き着く先は
同じなのかもしれない。
ただ 後者の生き方を選ぶとき➡
But when people have a choice,
人は
生きる目的に向かって頑張れる。
they can strive hard towards
their goal in life.
そして それを持つ者が
本当に強いのだと。
And, for someone to have that,
means they are truly strong.
そして
父上 私の目的は ただ一つ➡
And Father…
I have just one goal.
もっと強くなりたい
誰にも負けないくらい。
To become stronger.
To become someone who
cannot be defeated.
That's how I feel right now.
今はそう思います。
いい仲間が出来たな ネジ。
You've made a wonderful friend…
Neji.
(ネジ)今は ライバルですが…。
Although right now, he's a rival…
(ネジ)父上！
えっ！
Father!
どうやら 術を探さなくて
いいようだ。
Seems like we don't need to find
a way to release the jutsu.
ああ。
Yeah.
立派になったな ネジ。
You've grown up well.
父様！
Father!
父様…。
Father…
(ネジ)ガイ…。
Guy…
ヒザシさんは お前の成長する姿を
見届けられなかったことが➡
It seems Hizashi's greatest regret
was not being able to
guide you into adulthood.
いちばんの心残りだったようだな。
はい。
Yes.
(弥彦)
よかったな 皆も家に戻って➡
I'm glad the villagers are back home
and peace has returned to this village.
この村にも
平和が戻ったってわけだ。
ええ それで これからどうする？
Yes. So what do we do now?
木ノ葉隠れの里の下忍たちと
組む気なのか？
Are you thinking of joining up
with the Hidden Leaf Genin?
Yeah…
ああ。 里は違えど➡
Although we're from different villages,
I feel like we can call them comrades.
同志と言ってもいいかもな
って思っている。
Perhaps the day will come
when we'll team up with them.
いつか あいつらと組む日も
来るかもしれないな。 ん？
Nagato, what's that?
長門 なんだそれ。
あの子供たちの？
Doesn't it belong
to those children?
村の道で拾ったんだ。
I found it on the road
to the village.
みんなが村に帰るどさくさで
落としてしまったらしいな。
It was chaotic,
with everyone try
ハハハ！ あいつら➡
また ぬいぐるみがないって
大騒ぎしてるだろうな。
よし 俺が届けてきてやる。
弥彦…。
すぐ戻る ここで待っててくれ。
おっしゃ！ さっさと戻って
父ちゃんに報告するってばよ！
じゃあ ナルト君
里まで僕と競争しましょう！
フン 負けねえってばよ。
僕だって負けません。
俺が負けないんだってばよ！
僕もです。
俺だってばよ。
僕です！
ほんと元気ね。
そうね。
(カカシ)お～い 待ってくれ。
ま まだ体の調子が…。
ちょ ちょっと
休んでいきましょうよ。
やれやれ。
えっ。
なんだ… なんだってばよ。
弥彦。
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
長門？
うわぁ～！